<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Integrative Dashboard</title>
    <link>https://digitalgeosciences.github.io/dashboard3.2/</link>
    <description>Recent publications with OpenAlex abstracts and topics.</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:23:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>A Synergistic Chelating Approach for Hematite Filter Cake Removal in Carbonate Reservoirs Using DTPA and Citric Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/230890-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7127171301</guid>
      <dc:creator>Amir Shokry, Salaheldin Elkatatny, Badr Bageri, Vagif Suleymanov, Mustafa Al Ramadan, Abdulazeez Abdulraheem, Abdulrauf R. Adebayo</dc:creator>
      <category>Citric acid</category>
      <category>Chemistry</category>
      <category>Solubility</category>
      <category>Filter cake</category>
      <category>Dissolution</category>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract Efficient removal of hematite-based filter cake is critical for restoring formation permeability while minimizing secondary formation damage. Conventional hydrochloric acid treatments often lead to severe corrosion and iron precipitation when reacting with carbonate formations. In this study, a combined chelating system consisting of 10 wt% diethylenetriaminepentaacetic acid (DTPA) and 10 wt% citric acid was developed to dissolve hematite-based filter cake under formation-friendly conditions. The solution, maintained at a pH of 2.25, achieved a solubility of 3.4 g of hematite per 100 cc of solution after 18 hours at 185 °F. The combination of DTPA and citric acid provided a synergistic chelating capability that stabilized the dissolved iron species, preventing reprecipitation during pH increase caused by calcite dissolution. The inclusion of citric acid significantly reduced the required DTPA concentration—addressing the economic limitation of DTPA&apos;s high cost—while maintaining high iron-chelating efficiency. A systematic series of solubility tests was conducted to evaluate the effects of solution pH, temperature, and treatment time on the dissolution performance. Results showed that solubility increased with temperature and prolonged exposure time, reaching optimal performance after 18 hours. Laboratory-prepared filter cakes formed on ceramic disks exhibited 85% removal efficiency under the optimized conditions. Additionally, corrosion testing revealed substantially…&#10;Topics: Citric acid, Chemistry, Solubility, Filter cake, Dissolution&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Oil Recovery Through Eco-Driven CO2 Miscibility Enhancement in Crude Oil: Toward Efficient EOR and Carbon Sequestration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/231025-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7127125526</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed A. Al-Hakami, Ahmed Farid Ibrahim, Khaled Z. Abd Elgawad, Khaled Al-Azani</dc:creator>
      <category>Miscibility</category>
      <category>Enhanced oil recovery</category>
      <category>Seawater</category>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Carbonate</category>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract This study targets lowering the minimum miscibility pressure (MMP) and first-contact miscibility pressure (FCMP) of CO2–oil system to enable miscible/near-miscible CO2 flooding at safer, more practical injection pressures. We evaluate an eco-driven ionic liquid (IL), which is 1-methyl-3-octylimidazolium chloride ([C8mim]Cl), as a low-dosage additive to enhance CO2 miscibility and, in turn, improve oil recovery and CO2 potential storage in carbonate cores. ILs proved their potential to improve CO2 miscibility in crude oil and, due to that, different concentrations (0.25–0.75 wt%) of [C8mim]Cl were screened by vanishing interfacial tension (VIT) at 50 °C to quantify IFT–pressure trends and extract MMP and FCMP with and without [C8mim]Cl. The core flooding procedure used two composite Indiana-limestone plugs representing (a) base case, where secondary seawater injection followed by continuous CO2 injection is attained, (b) IL case, the same sequence but with a 1.5 PV pre-slug of 0.5 wt% [C8mim]Cl in seawater and around thirty hours soak before CO2 injection. VIT screening identified 0.5 wt% as the optimum [C8mim]Cl dose, lowering MMP from 1,642 psi to 1,499 psi and FCMP from 1,976 psi to 1,655 psi. These reductions can be identified in percentages as 8.7% and 16.27%, respectively. In core flooding, the IL pre-slug injected after secondary seawater flooding increased tertiary CO2 recovery from 29.7 % (base) to 39.7 % and raised total recovery from 82 % to 95.2%, correspo…&#10;Topics: Miscibility, Enhanced oil recovery, Seawater, Petroleum engineering, Carbonate&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Acidizing Technique in Carbonate Reservoir: An Experimental Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/231054-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7127114896</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Shehryar, Shabeeb Alajmei, Arshad Raza, Mohamed A. Mahmoud, Fahad Khan</dc:creator>
      <category>Carbonate</category>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Hydrochloric acid</category>
      <category>Permeability (electromagnetism)</category>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract Carbonate reservoirs, which account for a substantial portion of global hydrocarbon resources, often require acid stimulation to enhance permeability and improve well productivity. Conventional acidizing treatments typically involve the use of hydrochloric acid (HCl) to dissolve carbonate minerals such as calcite and dolomite. However, these treatments frequently encounter challenges including rapid acid-rock reactions in high-temperature reservoirs, inefficient acid utilization, and non-uniform penetration, which reduce the overall effectiveness of the stimulation process. Our study aims to develop an acidizing treatment composed of HCl and thermochemical additives for improved acid placement and acid-rock reaction control. The use of reactive additives leads to improved acid distribution in the formation and reduces early acid spending near the wellbore by reducing the local temperature. To assess the effectiveness of this new approach, laboratory core flood tests were done on carbonate rock samples. The tests showed that permeability improvement was much better than conventional acid systems, thus proving the effectiveness of the treatment enhanced with thermochemical additives. The new treatment gives us a feasible and scalable option to enhance the stimulation treatment in the carbonate reservoirs. The results provide a basis for improving the technique&apos;s design for implementing on the field in difficult reservoir conditions.&#10;Topics: Carbonate, Petroleum engineering, Hydrochloric acid, Permeability (electromagnetism), Environmental science&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Constrained Modulus in Predicting Resilient Modulus of RAP-Included Granular Materials via ML and Conventional Methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2026.109430</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7127331976</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Arshad, Muhammad Zaka Emad</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Results in Engineering</dc:publisher>
      <category>Granular material</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Composite material</category>
      <category>Modulus</category>
      <category>Young&apos;s modulus</category>
      <description>Topics: Granular material, Materials science, Composite material, Modulus, Young&apos;s modulus&#10;Venue: Results in Engineering&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonphotochemical shockwave-induced nucleation and time-resolved anisotropic crystal growth in KNO₃ solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2026.142683</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125949287</guid>
      <dc:creator>Watheq Al-Basheer, Musab Hashim, Ahmed M. El‐Zohry, Abdulaziz Aljalal, Said M. Al Azar, Khaled Gasmi</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Chemical Physics Letters</dc:publisher>
      <category>Nucleation</category>
      <category>Crystal growth</category>
      <category>Anisotropy</category>
      <category>Crystallography</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <description>Topics: Nucleation, Crystal growth, Anisotropy, Crystallography, Materials science&#10;Venue: Chemical Physics Letters&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating calcite as a catalyst for pyrite-hydrogen reactions and hydrogen sulfide generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engeos.2026.100525</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125487795</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Hammad Malik, Ahmed Al‐Yaseri, Khalid Al‐Ramadan</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Energy Geoscience</dc:publisher>
      <category>Pyrite</category>
      <category>Hydrogen sulfide</category>
      <category>Calcite</category>
      <category>Hydrogen</category>
      <category>Sulfur</category>
      <description>Abstract: In nature, the presence of accessory minerals found in the subsurface have a potential to react with stored hydrogen in process of underground hydrogen storage. Pyrite (FeS2), the most abundant sulfide mineral on earth and occurring in almost all geological rock formations specially the sedimentary rocks, is an ideal candidate for such reactions. Pyrite is also found in seal rocks in higher quantities and considered a critical mineral while working with subsurface hydrocarbon reservoirs. Although relatively stable at surface conditions, pyrite is still prone to oxidation in the presence of moisture and high temperatures found in subsurface reservoirs, leading to the release of sulfur. This sulfur can readily react with other elements, and in context of hydrogen storage in sedimentary rocks, it can react with hydrogen to form hydrogen sulfide (H2S) gas. H2S being extremely toxic, pose significant handling dangers along with potential degradation of the stored hydrogen fuel. Therefore, the presence of reactive and toxic material like H2S require careful consideration when evaluating subsurface hydrocarbon reservoirs for hydrogen storage. In this study, we examined the reaction of pyrite combined with varying concentrations of calcite (1 %, 5 %, and 50 %), brine water (3.5 wt% NaCl), and hydrogen gas (H2) under different reservoir conditions (120 °C and 250 °C, and 500 psi). The findings revealed that approximately 12 % H2S was released, irrespective of the calcite concentration…&#10;Topics: Pyrite, Hydrogen sulfide, Calcite, Hydrogen, Sulfur&#10;Venue: Energy Geoscience&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Gas–Brine Surface Tension Using Data-Driven Techniques for Underground Hydrogen Storage: A Focus on Depleted Gas Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.5c10951</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125479255</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed Sofian, Abdulazeez Abdulraheem, Talal Al Shafloot, Salaheldin Elkatatny, Naif Alqahtani</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>ACS Omega</dc:publisher>
      <category>Focus (optics)</category>
      <category>Surface tension</category>
      <category>Hydrogen</category>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <description>Topics: Focus (optics), Surface tension, Hydrogen, Environmental science, Geology&#10;Venue: ACS Omega&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Spectroscopic and First-Principles Study of Dirac Semimetal Cd3As2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10904-026-04178-z</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124748454</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sheena Shah, Kh. A. Ziq, Ahmed M. El‐Zohry, Anas Y. Al-Reyahi, Said M. Al Azar, Abdulaziz Aljalal, Saber Sâad Essaoud, Watheq Al-Basheer</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of Inorganic and Organometallic Polymers and Materials</dc:publisher>
      <category>Semimetal</category>
      <category>Dirac (video compression format)</category>
      <category>Physics</category>
      <category>Condensed matter physics</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <description>Topics: Semimetal, Dirac (video compression format), Physics, Condensed matter physics, Materials science&#10;Venue: Journal of Inorganic and Organometallic Polymers and Materials&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extrapolation of seismic land streamer data using interferometry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-026-35328-5</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124692653</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sherif M. Hanafy</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Scientific Reports</dc:publisher>
      <category>Extrapolation</category>
      <category>Interferometry</category>
      <category>Remote sensing</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Geodesy</category>
      <description>Topics: Extrapolation, Interferometry, Remote sensing, Geology, Geodesy&#10;Venue: Scientific Reports&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quaternionic superconductivity with a single-field Bogoliubov-de Gennes--Ginzburg-Landau framework and charge-4e couplings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2601.12264</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125263942</guid>
      <dc:creator>Christian Tantardini, Sabri Elatresh</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Physics</category>
      <category>Pairing</category>
      <category>Quaternion</category>
      <category>Antisymmetric relation</category>
      <category>Covariant transformation</category>
      <description>Abstract: We recast spinful superconductivity as a quaternion field theory -- where a quaternion is a four-component hypercomplex number with units $(\boldsymbol{i},\boldsymbol{j},\boldsymbol{k})$ -- that encodes the spin-singlet/triplet gap in a single field $q(\mathbf{k})$. This yields a compact Bogoliubov--de Gennes (BdG) Hamiltonian $H_{\rm BdG}=ξ_{\mathbf{k}}τ_z+τ_{+}q+τ_{-}\,\overline{q}$ and keeps time-reversal symmetry, Altland-Zirnbauer classification, and topological diagnostics in the same variables. We introduce a quarteting field $Q\propto\mathrm{Sc}(q^2)$ and a minimal Ginzburg-Landau (GL) functional with covariant derivatives $(\nabla-2ie\mathbf{A})q$ and $(\nabla-4ie\mathbf{A})Q$. Analytically, a one-loop evaluation of the fluctuation bubble $Π(0)$ (with prefactors) gives a quantitative vestigial charge-$4e$ criterion $μ_{\rm eff}=μ-g^2Π(0)&amp;lt;0$. Numerically, we verify: (i) a two-dimensional (2D) class-DIII lattice model whose $\mathbb{Z}_2$ index, computed directly from $q(\mathbf{k})$ using the matrix Pfaffian of an antisymmetric sewing matrix at time-reversal-invariant momenta (TRIM), matches helical edge spectra; (ii) a GL simulation of a pure-$Q$ vortex carrying $hc/4e$ flux within $\sim2\%$ and exhibiting $ξ_Q\propto\sqrt{η/|μ_{\rm eff}|}$; and (iii) a short-junction current-phase relation with a controlled window where the second harmonic dominates ($I_2\gg I_1$), together with doubled alternating-current (ac) Josephson emission and even-only Shapiro steps. The …&#10;Topics: Physics, Pairing, Quaternion, Antisymmetric relation, Covariant transformation&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quaternionic superconductivity with a single-field Bogoliubov-de Gennes--Ginzburg-Landau framework and charge-4e couplings</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W7125351706</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125351706</guid>
      <dc:creator>Christian Tantardini, Sabri Elatresh</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Physics</category>
      <category>Pairing</category>
      <category>Quaternion</category>
      <category>Antisymmetric relation</category>
      <category>Covariant transformation</category>
      <description>Abstract: We recast spinful superconductivity as a quaternion field theory -- where a quaternion is a four-component hypercomplex number with units $(\boldsymbol{i},\boldsymbol{j},\boldsymbol{k})$ -- that encodes the spin-singlet/triplet gap in a single field $q(\mathbf{k})$. This yields a compact Bogoliubov--de Gennes (BdG) Hamiltonian $H_{\rm BdG}=ξ_{\mathbf{k}}τ_z+τ_{+}q+τ_{-}\,\overline{q}$ and keeps time-reversal symmetry, Altland-Zirnbauer classification, and topological diagnostics in the same variables. We introduce a quarteting field $Q\propto\mathrm{Sc}(q^2)$ and a minimal Ginzburg-Landau (GL) functional with covariant derivatives $(\nabla-2ie\mathbf{A})q$ and $(\nabla-4ie\mathbf{A})Q$. Analytically, a one-loop evaluation of the fluctuation bubble $Π(0)$ (with prefactors) gives a quantitative vestigial charge-$4e$ criterion $μ_{\rm eff}=μ-g^2Π(0)&lt;0$. Numerically, we verify: (i) a two-dimensional (2D) class-DIII lattice model whose $\mathbb{Z}_2$ index, computed directly from $q(\mathbf{k})$ using the matrix Pfaffian of an antisymmetric sewing matrix at time-reversal-invariant momenta (TRIM), matches helical edge spectra; (ii) a GL simulation of a pure-$Q$ vortex carrying $hc/4e$ flux within $\sim2\%$ and exhibiting $ξ_Q\propto\sqrt{η/|μ_{\rm eff}|}$; and (iii) a short-junction current-phase relation with a controlled window where the second harmonic dominates ($I_2\gg I_1$), together with doubled alternating-current (ac) Josephson emission and even-only Shapiro steps. The fra…&#10;Topics: Physics, Pairing, Quaternion, Antisymmetric relation, Covariant transformation&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perlite-modified micromax-based drilling fluids: improved filtration control and rheological performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13202-025-02101-9</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124527367</guid>
      <dc:creator>Jaber B. Al Jaberi, Badr Bageri, Salaheldin Elkatatny</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of Petroleum Exploration and Production Technology</dc:publisher>
      <category>Offshore geotechnical engineering</category>
      <category>Rheology</category>
      <category>Filtration (mathematics)</category>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Drilling</category>
      <description>Topics: Offshore geotechnical engineering, Rheology, Filtration (mathematics), Petroleum engineering, Drilling&#10;Venue: Journal of Petroleum Exploration and Production Technology&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representative-volume sizing in finite cylindrical computed tomography by low-wavenumber spectral convergence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2601.09283</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124278131</guid>
      <dc:creator>Fernando Alonso-Marroquin, Abdullah Alqubalee, Christian Tantardini</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      <category>Cylinder</category>
      <category>Convergence (economics)</category>
      <category>Position (finance)</category>
      <category>Finite element method</category>
      <description>Abstract: Choosing a representative element volume (REV) from finite cylindrical $μ$CT scans becomes ambiguous when a key field variable exhibits a slow axial trend, because estimated statistics can change systematically with subvolume size and position rather than converging under simple averaging. A practical workflow is presented to size an REV under such nonstationary conditions by first suppressing axial drift/trend to obtain a residual field suitable for second-order analysis, and then selecting the smallest analysis diameter for which low-wavenumber content stabilizes within a prescribed tolerance. The approach is demonstrated on \textit{Thalassinoides}-bearing rocks, whose branching, connected burrow networks impose heterogeneity on length scales comparable to typical laboratory core diameters, making imaging-based microstructural statistics and downstream digital-rock proxies highly sensitive to the chosen subvolume. From segmented data, a scalar ``burrowsity&apos;&apos; field--capturing burrow-related pore spaces and infills--is defined, and axial detrending (with optional normalization) is applied to mitigate acquisition drift and nonstationary trends. Representativeness is then posed as a diameter-convergence problem on nested inscribed cylinders: the two-point covariance and its isotropic spectral counterpart $\widehat{C}$ are estimated, and the smallest diameter at which the low-wavenumber plateau becomes stable is selected. Applied to a segmented \textit{Thalassinoides} core, the …&#10;Topics: Mathematics, Cylinder, Convergence (economics), Position (finance), Finite element method&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Representative-volume sizing in finite cylindrical computed tomography by low-wavenumber spectral convergence</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W7124358305</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124358305</guid>
      <dc:creator>Fernando Alonso-Marroquin, Abdullah Alqubalee, Christian Tantardini</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      <category>Cylinder</category>
      <category>Convergence (economics)</category>
      <category>Position (finance)</category>
      <category>Finite element method</category>
      <description>Abstract: Choosing a representative element volume (REV) from finite cylindrical $μ$CT scans becomes ambiguous when a key field variable exhibits a slow axial trend, because estimated statistics can change systematically with subvolume size and position rather than converging under simple averaging. A practical workflow is presented to size an REV under such nonstationary conditions by first suppressing axial drift/trend to obtain a residual field suitable for second-order analysis, and then selecting the smallest analysis diameter for which low-wavenumber content stabilizes within a prescribed tolerance. The approach is demonstrated on \textit{Thalassinoides}-bearing rocks, whose branching, connected burrow networks impose heterogeneity on length scales comparable to typical laboratory core diameters, making imaging-based microstructural statistics and downstream digital-rock proxies highly sensitive to the chosen subvolume. From segmented data, a scalar ``burrowsity&apos;&apos; field--capturing burrow-related pore spaces and infills--is defined, and axial detrending (with optional normalization) is applied to mitigate acquisition drift and nonstationary trends. Representativeness is then posed as a diameter-convergence problem on nested inscribed cylinders: the two-point covariance and its isotropic spectral counterpart $\widehat{C}$ are estimated, and the smallest diameter at which the low-wavenumber plateau becomes stable is selected. Applied to a segmented \textit{Thalassinoides} core, the …&#10;Topics: Mathematics, Cylinder, Convergence (economics), Position (finance), Finite element method&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the Air Gap: A Comprehensive Workflow for Integrating Drone Data Into the Digital Oilfield (DOF)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2523/iptc-25169-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7123348385</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Abualhareth Hassan, Sami Alnuaim</dc:creator>
      <category>Workflow</category>
      <category>Interoperability</category>
      <category>Drone</category>
      <category>Cloud computing</category>
      <category>Data governance</category>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract This paper addresses a critical industry gap: the absence of a standardized, comprehensive framework for integrating diverse drone-collected data into Digital Oilfield (DOF) infrastructures. A detailed, end-to-end workflow is presented to transform raw data from unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) into actionable intelligence across onshore and offshore operations while maintaining alignment with industry standards and cybersecurity requirements. The proposed five-stage workflow covering data acquisition, pre-processing, data management and integration, analytics, and application enablement, combines established industry data standards such as WITSML, PRODML, and OSDU with modern drone technologies, cloud platforms, and advanced analytics. Each stage outlines technical specifications, best practices, and NIST-aligned cybersecurity measures to ensure reliability and data integrity across the enterprise. The framework mitigates integration risk through standardized data mapping and quality assurance, supports real-time fusion of multi-modal sensors (visual, thermal, LiDAR, and gas), and enables advanced DOF applications including predictive integrity, anomaly detection, and environmental compliance (methane LDAR). Key integration challenges ranging from cybersecurity and interoperability to data governance are addressed with best-in-class, standards-aligned solutions, enabling safe, secure, and efficient drone-to-DOF operations. Finally, A practical case from ADNOC, integr…&#10;Topics: Workflow, Interoperability, Drone, Cloud computing, Data governance&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Based Prediction of Rock Mechanical Properties Using XRD, XRF, and Gamma Ray Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2523/iptc-25203-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7123355297</guid>
      <dc:creator>J. L. Davalos-Monteiro, C. D. Rodriguez-Hernandez, A. E. Ghreizy, R. M. Rached, R. L. Davalos, Mutasim Osman, K. Aryanci</dc:creator>
      <category>Coring</category>
      <category>Support vector machine</category>
      <category>Drilling</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Data set</category>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract This study explores the use of machine learning to predict mechanical properties of subsurface rocks, such as indentation-based Elastic modulus, using input features from X-ray diffraction (XRD), X-ray fluorescence (XRF), and gamma ray measurements. Traditional mechanical testing is costly, time-intensive, and often unfeasible for large datasets. Our goal is to develop a predictive tool that leverages accessible field and laboratory data to estimate geomechanical behavior, enabling real-time formation evaluation during drilling. By integrating in-situ measurements such as gamma ray logs while drilling and surface XRD/XRF analysis from cuttings, this approach supports live monitoring of the drilling process and improves on-site decision making without the need for routine lab-based mechanical testing. The dataset for this study was developed from direct experimental measurements on rock samples obtained during coring operations. All measurements were carried out in the laboratory: gamma ray signals were acquired through core scanning, mineralogical composition was determined using XRD, and elemental content was measured with XRF. Mechanical properties were then quantified through depth-resolved micro-indentation testing, ensuring that both geophysical and geochemical data were consistently tied to the same set of core samples. To evaluate predictive performance, we trained and validated multiple machine learning models, including Random Forest, XGBoost, Gradient Boost…&#10;Topics: Coring, Support vector machine, Drilling, Geology, Data set&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gauge-invariant long-wavelength TDDFT without empty states: From polarizability to Kubo conductivity across heterogeneous materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0310849</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7122497980</guid>
      <dc:creator>Christian Tantardini, Quentin Pitteloud, Boris I. Yakobson, Martin Andersson</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>The Journal of Chemical Physics</dc:publisher>
      <category>Dielectric</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Kubo formula</category>
      <category>Polarizability</category>
      <category>Polarization (electrochemistry)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Electromagnetic response is commonly computed in two languages: length-gauge molecular polarizabilities and velocity-gauge (Kubo) conductivities for periodic solids. We introduce a compact, gauge-invariant bridge that carries the same microscopic inputs—transition dipoles and interaction kernels—from molecules to crystals and heterogeneous media, with explicit SI prefactors and fine-structure scaling via αfs. The long-wavelength limit is handled through a reduced dielectric matrix that retains local-field mixing; interfaces and 2D layers are treated with sheet boundary conditions (rather than naïve ultrathin films); and length–velocity equivalence is enforced in practice by including the equal-time (diamagnetic/contact) term alongside the paramagnetic current. Finite temperature is addressed on the Matsubara axis with numerically stable real-axis evaluation (complex polarization propagator), preserving unit consistency end-to-end. The framework enables predictive, unit-faithful observables from radio frequency to ultraviolet—RF/microwave heating and penetration depth, dielectric-logging contrast, interfacial optics of thin films and 2D sheets, and adsorption metrics via imaginary-axis polarizabilities. Numerical checks (gauge overlay and optical f-sum saturation) validate the implementation. Immediate priorities include compact, temperature- and salinity-aware kernels with quantified uncertainties and operando interfacial diagnostics for integration into multiphysics digital …&#10;Topics: Dielectric, Materials science, Kubo formula, Polarizability, Polarization (electrochemistry)&#10;Venue: The Journal of Chemical Physics&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular dynamics insights into urease stability under reservoir conditions: Implications for sustainable bio-cementation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2026.121124</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7120209356</guid>
      <dc:creator>Safwat Abdel‐Azeim</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of environmental chemical engineering</dc:publisher>
      <category>Chemistry</category>
      <category>Molecular dynamics</category>
      <category>Urease</category>
      <category>Stability (learning theory)</category>
      <category>Environmental chemistry</category>
      <description>Topics: Chemistry, Molecular dynamics, Urease, Stability (learning theory), Environmental chemistry&#10;Venue: Journal of environmental chemical engineering&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning chitosan retention and performance in enhanced oil recovery via hydrophobic side chain modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2026.172701</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7118701917</guid>
      <dc:creator>Alexandra Scerbacova, Safwat Abdel‐Azeim, Mahmoud A. Abdulhamid</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Chemical Engineering Journal</dc:publisher>
      <category>Side chain</category>
      <category>Chemistry</category>
      <category>Chitosan</category>
      <category>Chemical engineering</category>
      <category>Enhanced oil recovery</category>
      <description>Topics: Side chain, Chemistry, Chitosan, Chemical engineering, Enhanced oil recovery&#10;Venue: Chemical Engineering Journal&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic CO2 storage capacity appraisal of the Greensand Project in the depleted Nini oil field, offshore Denmark</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.138226</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7118997177</guid>
      <dc:creator>Khaled Ahmed Mohammed Al-Raeeini, Ose Budiman, Ruud Weijermars</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Fuel</dc:publisher>
      <category>Submarine pipeline</category>
      <category>Probabilistic logic</category>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <description>Topics: Submarine pipeline, Probabilistic logic, Environmental science, Petroleum engineering, Geology&#10;Venue: Fuel&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing soil cover systems for coal gangue reclamation: balancing leachate control, environmental risk, and cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-32202-8</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7118165654</guid>
      <dc:creator>Xu Liu, Zhenqi Hu, Jingwei Gao</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Scientific Reports</dc:publisher>
      <category>Leachate</category>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Cover (algebra)</category>
      <category>Coal</category>
      <category>Waste management</category>
      <description>Topics: Leachate, Environmental science, Cover (algebra), Coal, Waste management&#10;Venue: Scientific Reports&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Aqueous Leaves Extracts of Individual and Polyherbal Formulated Ointments in Demonstration of Elastic Fibres on Wound Healing of Wounded Skin of Wistar Rats</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/ajrb/2026/v16i1464</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7119872157</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abubakar Usman, James Olayinka Adisa, Isah Mohammed, Mohammed Salisu Abubakar, Musa Ozovehe Mohammed, Isah Rilwanu Tsamiya, Abdu Umar</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Asian Journal of Research in Biochemistry</dc:publisher>
      <category>Aloe vera</category>
      <category>Traditional medicine</category>
      <category>Wound healing</category>
      <category>Aqueous extract</category>
      <category>Calotropis procera</category>
      <description>Abstract: Wound defined as a loss or breaking of epithelial cellular. Wound healing is a complex process that is dependent on several factors that may hasten or affect the process of wound healing activity. The aim of the study was to assess the effects of aqueous leaves extract of individual and polyherbal formulated ointments in wounded skin of wistar rats. Total of 45 healthy wistar rats were divided into 9 groups, with 5 rats in each. Group A negative control, wounded no treatment, group B positive control, wounded and treated with standard drug, group C test wounded treated with aqueous extract of A nilotica only, group D test wounded treated with aqueous leaves extract of A. vera only, group E test group wounded and treated with aqueous leaves extract of C. procera only, group F test wounded treated with combinations of aqueous leaves extract of A. nilotica and A. vera, group G wounded treated with combinations of aqueous leaf extract of A. nilotica and C. procera, the group H wounded treated with aqueous leaves extract of aloe vera and C. procera and group I test wounded treated with aqueous leaves extract of polyherbal formulation of A. nilotica, A. vera and C. procera. The result of the study showed that extracts of A. nilotica has better physical properties than other extracts, The aqueous leaves extract the Acacia nilotica, Aloe vera and Calotropis procera shows very good physical characteristics and presence of secondary metabolites that possessed wound healing effect. In c…&#10;Topics: Aloe vera, Traditional medicine, Wound healing, Aqueous extract, Calotropis procera&#10;Venue: Asian Journal of Research in Biochemistry&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Multifrequency Dielectric Technique for Analyzing Foam Flow in Porous Media for Enhanced Oil Recovery and CO2 Sequestration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/218924-pa</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125515389</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Bashir, Amjed Mohammed Hassan, Hussein Attia, Assad Barri, Ridha Al-Abdrabalnabi, Shirish Patil, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, A. A. El-Husseiny, Mahmoud Ma</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SPE Journal</dc:publisher>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Dielectric</category>
      <category>Enhanced oil recovery</category>
      <category>Porous medium</category>
      <category>Conductivity</category>
      <description>Abstract: Summary Foam has been widely used to control gas mobility during subsurface oil displacement processes, mitigating challenges such as reservoir heterogeneity, gas channeling, and gravity override. Its applications extend to enhanced oil recovery (EOR) and CO2 storage, where foam improves sweep efficiency and reduces gas leakage. However, the thermodynamic instability of foam necessitates a reliable evaluation of its quality and stability before field deployment. This work introduces a novel multifrequency dielectric technique for characterizing both bulk foam and foam flow in porous media. This study presents the first application of a multifrequency dielectric technique for foam characterization, validated against conventional foam analyzer measurements of quality and stability. In the first part of the study, dielectric properties (permittivity and conductivity) were measured for bulk foams generated with sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) surfactant at two concentrations (0.1 wt% and 0.3 wt%) using deionized water (DW) and seawater (SW). Measurements were performed across a 1-MHz to 3-GHz frequency range using an open-ended coaxial probe connected to a Keysight impedance analyzer, and results were compared with those from a standard foam analyzer. The findings showed that conductivity increased with frequency due to ion polarization, particularly at low to intermediate frequencies. Foams generated with SDS in DW exhibited lower permittivity than bulk water, reflecting the reduce…&#10;Topics: Materials science, Dielectric, Enhanced oil recovery, Porous medium, Conductivity&#10;Venue: SPE Journal&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Three-Dimensional Magnetotelluric Modeling for Geothermal Exploration in Al-Lith, Western Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.6083033</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125705953</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abdul Latif Ashadi, Bülent Tezkan, Pritam Yogeshwar, Panagiotis Kirmizakis, Tilman Hanstein, Pantelis Soupios</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SSRN Electronic Journal</dc:publisher>
      <category>Magnetotellurics</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Geothermal gradient</category>
      <category>Remote sensing</category>
      <category>Mining engineering</category>
      <description>Topics: Magnetotellurics, Geology, Geothermal gradient, Remote sensing, Mining engineering&#10;Venue: SSRN Electronic Journal&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative technologies to enhance crude oil recovery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-34088-8.00114-2</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124425216</guid>
      <dc:creator>Masooma Nazar, Xiao Deng, Muhammad Israr, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, Syed Muhammad Shakil Hussain</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Elsevier eBooks</dc:publisher>
      <category>Crude oil</category>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Waste management</category>
      <category>Process engineering</category>
      <category>Synthetic crude</category>
      <description>Topics: Crude oil, Environmental science, Waste management, Process engineering, Synthetic crude&#10;Venue: Elsevier eBooks&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solubility and interfacial tension of hydrogen and hydrogen-methane mixtures in water: Effect of pH, salinity, and gas composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.153276</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7118018497</guid>
      <dc:creator>Norah Aljeban, Amer Alanazi, Khaled Abdelgawad, Assad Barri, Jafar Al Hamad, Hussein Hoteit</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>International Journal of Hydrogen Energy</dc:publisher>
      <category>Solubility</category>
      <category>Hydrogen</category>
      <category>Surface tension</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Composition (language)</category>
      <description>Topics: Solubility, Hydrogen, Surface tension, Materials science, Composition (language)&#10;Venue: International Journal of Hydrogen Energy&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A two-organoclay formulation approach for enhanced performance of oil-based drilling fluids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.petlm.2025.12.003</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7118094296</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ali Mahmoud, Rahul Gajbhiye, Salaheldin Elkatatny</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Petroleum</dc:publisher>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Drilling fluid</category>
      <category>Drilling</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <description>Topics: Petroleum engineering, Materials science, Drilling fluid, Drilling, Geology&#10;Venue: Petroleum&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen loss in depleted carbonate reservoirs: Experimental study of geochemical and mechanical effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.153103</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7118474809</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed Lardhi, Bashirul Haq, Dhafer AlShehri, Abduljamiu Amao, Sulaiman Alarifi, Mohamed Mahmoud, Shirish Patil</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>International Journal of Hydrogen Energy</dc:publisher>
      <category>Carbonate</category>
      <category>Hydrogen</category>
      <category>Chemistry</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Hydrogen production</category>
      <description>Topics: Carbonate, Hydrogen, Chemistry, Materials science, Hydrogen production&#10;Venue: International Journal of Hydrogen Energy&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determining stress ratio using back analysis from the actual tunnel convergence for designing underground structures in hard rocks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.6145983</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7125915665</guid>
      <dc:creator>Furqan Hameed, Mehran Khan, Muhammad Zaka Emad</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SSRN Electronic Journal</dc:publisher>
      <category>Stress (linguistics)</category>
      <category>Convergence (economics)</category>
      <category>Geotechnical engineering</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Engineering</category>
      <description>Topics: Stress (linguistics), Convergence (economics), Geotechnical engineering, Geology, Engineering&#10;Venue: SSRN Electronic Journal&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient absorption spectroscopy: a mechanistic tool for triplet sensitizers and their applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d5cs00614g</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7123229459</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mushraf Hussain, Samana Batool, Zafar Mahmood, Nooreen Rehmat, Ahmed M. El‐Zohry, Zhao, Mariangela Di Donato, Matthew C. T. Hartman, Katharine Moore Tibbetts</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Chemical Society Reviews</dc:publisher>
      <category>Photoexcitation</category>
      <category>Intersystem crossing</category>
      <category>Ultrafast laser spectroscopy</category>
      <category>Photochemistry</category>
      <category>Excimer</category>
      <description>Abstract: Transient absorption spectroscopy is used to study events that take place upon photoexcitation and reveal the processes such as electron transfer, energy transfer, intersystem crossing, isomerization, proton transfer, exciplex formation, etc .&#10;Topics: Photoexcitation, Intersystem crossing, Ultrafast laser spectroscopy, Photochemistry, Excimer&#10;Venue: Chemical Society Reviews&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User-to-User Clustering, Channel Estimation &amp;amp; Cross-Link Interference Mitigation for Dynamic TDD Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ojsp.2026.3654888</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7124426948</guid>
      <dc:creator>Martin Andersson, Anubhab Chowdhury, Erik G. Larsson</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>IEEE Open Journal of Signal Processing</dc:publisher>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <category>Interference (communication)</category>
      <category>Channel (broadcasting)</category>
      <category>Electronic engineering</category>
      <category>Noise (video)</category>
      <description>Topics: Computer science, Interference (communication), Channel (broadcasting), Electronic engineering, Noise (video)&#10;Venue: IEEE Open Journal of Signal Processing&#10;Year: 2026&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced anomaly detection in well log data through the application of ensemble GANs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.acags.2025.100316</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117782240</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abdulrahman Al‐Fakih, Ardiansyah Koeshidayatullah, Mukerji T., SanLinn I. Kaka</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Applied Computing and Geosciences</dc:publisher>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <category>Anomaly detection</category>
      <category>Pattern recognition (psychology)</category>
      <category>Artificial intelligence</category>
      <category>Algorithm</category>
      <description>Topics: Computer science, Anomaly detection, Pattern recognition (psychology), Artificial intelligence, Algorithm&#10;Venue: Applied Computing and Geosciences&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of uncertainty in Utsira formation temperature and salinity on CO2 storage: A field-scale reactive transport simulation study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100567</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117899486</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mohamed Gamal Rezk, Ahmed Farid Ibrahim</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology</dc:publisher>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Salinity</category>
      <category>Carbon dioxide</category>
      <category>Work (physics)</category>
      <category>Atmospheric sciences</category>
      <description>Topics: Environmental science, Salinity, Carbon dioxide, Work (physics), Atmospheric sciences&#10;Venue: Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Reservoir Conditions on CO2 Miscibility in Crude Oils: Implications for CO2 Sequestration and Enhanced Oil Recovery Projects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.64589/juri/214392</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7119108170</guid>
      <dc:creator>Noor Al-Sadig, Mohamed Gamal Rezk</dc:creator>
      <category>Miscibility</category>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Enhanced oil recovery</category>
      <category>Petroleum</category>
      <category>Solubility</category>
      <description>Abstract: CO2 injection has emerged as a pivotal technique in the petroleum industry, offering a cost-effective option to enhance oil recovery while contributing to improved environmental sustainability. The mass transfer of CO2 into reservoir fluids is the primary mechanism responsible for CO2 solubility trapping and enhancement of oil recovery. The minimum miscibility pressure between CO2 and crude oils controls the performance of any CO2-enhanced oil recovery (EOR) and storage project. This paper investigates the influence of reservoir conditions on the CO2-oil miscibility during CO2 injection in oil reservoirs. To do so, pendant drop tests were conducted, and CO2-oil interfacial tension (IFT) was measured at different pressures and two temperatures. The minimum miscibility pressure (MMP) and first contact miscibility pressure (FCM) between the CO2 and crude oil were estimated from the measured IFT values by applying the vanishing interfacial tension (VIT) technique. The measured MMP was found to increase with reservoir temperature as MMP increased from 1175 psi at T=27°C to 2007 psi at T=70°C. Similarly, the FCM pressure was found to significantly increase with reservoir temperature. This research provides a valuable guide for screening oil reservoirs suitable for EOR and CO2 storage.&#10;Topics: Miscibility, Petroleum engineering, Enhanced oil recovery, Petroleum, Solubility&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Aqueous Leaves Extracts of Individual and Polyherbal Formulated Ointments on Wound Healing with the Demonstration of Epitheliasation and Angiogenesis in Wounded Skin of Wistar Rats</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W7119400636</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7119400636</guid>
      <dc:creator>Usman Abubakar, James O. Adisa, Isah Mohammed, Mohammed Salisu, Abubakar Musa Ozovehe Mohammed, Isah Rilwanu Tsamiya, Muhammad, Ahmad, Tangaza, Abdu Umar</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Wound healing</category>
      <category>Angiogenesis</category>
      <category>Aqueous extract</category>
      <category>Traditional medicine</category>
      <category>Medicine</category>
      <description>Abstract: International audience&#10;Topics: Wound healing, Angiogenesis, Aqueous extract, Traditional medicine, Medicine&#10;Venue: HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Aqueous Leaves Extracts of Individual and Polyherbal Formulated Ointments on Wound Healing with the Demonstration of Epitheliasation and Angiogenesis in Wounded Skin of Wistar Rats</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/jocamr/2025/v26i12730</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7119499426</guid>
      <dc:creator>Usman Abubakar, James Olayinka Adisa, Isah Mohammed, Mohammed Salisu, Musa Ozovehe Mohammed Abubakar, Isah Rilwanu Tsamiya, Ahmad Tangaza Muhammad, Abdu Umar</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of Complementary and Alternative Medical Research</dc:publisher>
      <category>Traditional medicine</category>
      <category>Aqueous extract</category>
      <category>Wound healing</category>
      <category>Aqueous solution</category>
      <category>Aloe vera</category>
      <description>Abstract: The aim of the study was to assess the effects of aqueous leaves extract of individual and polyherbal formulated ointments in wounded skin of wistar rats. Total of 45 healthy wistar rats were divided into 9 groups, with 5 rats in each. Group A negative control, wounded no treatment, group B positive control, wounded and treated with standard drug, group C test wounded treated with aqueous extract of A nilotica only, group D test wounded treated with aqueous leaves extract of A. vera only, group six E test group wounded and treated with aqueous leaves extract of C. procera only, group F test wounded treated with combinations of aqueous leaves extract of A. nilotica and A. vera, group G wounded treated with combinations of aqueous leaf extract of A. nilotica and C. procera, the group H wounded treated with aqueous leaves extract of aloe vera and C. procera and group I test wounded treated with aqueous leaves extract of polyherbal formulation of A. nilotica, A. vera and C. procera. The result of the study showed that extracts of A. nilotica has better physical properties than other extracts with good bioactive compounds, The combination of the three extracts showed better significant histological findings than A. nilotica. There was normal expression of vascular endothelial growth factors gene in group treated with individual A. nilotica extract and in combination of the three extracts. Similar results were also observed in expression of transforming growth factor gene bete-1 an…&#10;Topics: Traditional medicine, Aqueous extract, Wound healing, Aqueous solution, Aloe vera&#10;Venue: Journal of Complementary and Alternative Medical Research&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test FraCSPy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.18093151</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117664858</guid>
      <dc:creator>Denis Anikiev</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Test (biology)</category>
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <category>Artificial intelligence</category>
      <category>Relation (database)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Test release for FraCSPy.&#10;Topics: Test (biology), Mathematics, Computer science, Artificial intelligence, Relation (database)&#10;Venue: Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test FraCSPy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.18093142</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117669897</guid>
      <dc:creator>Denis Anikiev</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Test (biology)</category>
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <category>Artificial intelligence</category>
      <category>Relation (database)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Test release for FraCSPy.&#10;Topics: Test (biology), Mathematics, Computer science, Artificial intelligence, Relation (database)&#10;Venue: Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoSIRR: Geological Section Interpretation, Reconstruction &amp; Refinement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.18097053</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117703134</guid>
      <dc:creator>Denis Anikiev, Juan Esteban Mosquera</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Section (typography)</category>
      <category>Python (programming language)</category>
      <category>Geologic map</category>
      <category>Narrative</category>
      <description>Abstract: GeoSIRR (Geological Section Interpretation, Reconstruction &amp; Refinement) is an open-source Python Framework that leverages large language models (LLMs) to translate free-form geological narratives into structured, coordinate-based cross-section geometries.&#10;Topics: Geology, Section (typography), Python (programming language), Geologic map, Narrative&#10;Venue: Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GeoSIRR: Geological Section Interpretation, Reconstruction &amp; Refinement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.18097054</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117771395</guid>
      <dc:creator>Denis Anikiev, Juan Esteban Mosquera</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Section (typography)</category>
      <category>Python (programming language)</category>
      <category>Geologic map</category>
      <category>Narrative</category>
      <description>Abstract: GeoSIRR (Geological Section Interpretation, Reconstruction &amp; Refinement) is an open-source Python Framework that leverages large language models (LLMs) to translate free-form geological narratives into structured, coordinate-based cross-section geometries.&#10;Topics: Geology, Section (typography), Python (programming language), Geologic map, Narrative&#10;Venue: Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced CNN-based remote sensing for mineral mapping of porphyry systems in the Gilgit region</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33271/mining19.04.053</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117566586</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Munzareen, Feroz Bibi, Salman Ihsan, Kausar Sultan Shah, Muhammad Zaka Emad</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Mining of Mineral Deposits</dc:publisher>
      <category>Remote sensing</category>
      <category>Terrain</category>
      <category>Identification (biology)</category>
      <category>Mineral exploration</category>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <description>Abstract: Purpose. This study aims to improve mineral identification in porphyry hydrothermal alteration zones, particularly in the challenging terrain of the Gilgit area, by combining remote sensing data with Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs). Methods. Landsat 8 Collection 2 Level 1 imagery from the United States Geological Survey (USGS) was processed using ENVI 5.3 software. Spectral Angle Mapping (SAM) classification was applied to identify alteration minerals. The dataset was then augmented, normalized, and split into training (75%), validation (15%), and testing (15%) sets. A CNN model incorporating convolutional, pooling, and fully connected layers was developed to perform binary classification of mineral compositions. Findings. Advanced CNN-based remote sensing techniques have demonstrated significant potential in mapping porphyry systems. The CNN model achieved over 90% classification accuracy for minerals like feldspar and chalcocite, based on their spectral properties and dominant color features. This approach is beneficial in challenging terrains like Gilgit, where traditio-nal methods can be difficult and expensive. Originality. This study demonstrates the successful integration of remote sensing data with CNN-based algorithms for accurate mineral classification, providing a novel approach to overcoming the limitations of conventional field-based methods in challenging terrains. Practical implications. The approach provides a practical and efficient solution for remote m…&#10;Topics: Remote sensing, Terrain, Identification (biology), Mineral exploration, Computer science&#10;Venue: Mining of Mineral Deposits&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test FraCSPy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.18086589</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117536541</guid>
      <dc:creator>Denis Anikiev</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Test (biology)</category>
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <category>Artificial intelligence</category>
      <category>Relation (database)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Test release for FraCSPy.&#10;Topics: Test (biology), Mathematics, Computer science, Artificial intelligence, Relation (database)&#10;Venue: Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of aquifer hydraulics and pumping well yield for supplemental paddy crop irrigation using pumping tests in Perak, Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10333-025-01055-2</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117488147</guid>
      <dc:creator>Naseem Akhtar, Muhammad Syakir, Syahidah Akmal Muhammad, Aznan Fazli Ismail, Mohamad Shaiful Md Yusuff, Leila Bouida, Hamza Mohamed Flafel, Pahmi Husain, Mohammed Benaafi, Taskin Ahmed, Mohammad Muqtada Ali Khan</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Paddy and Water Environment</dc:publisher>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Irrigation</category>
      <category>Aquifer</category>
      <category>Hydrogeology</category>
      <category>Yield (engineering)</category>
      <description>Topics: Environmental science, Irrigation, Aquifer, Hydrogeology, Yield (engineering)&#10;Venue: Paddy and Water Environment&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induced polarization effects in transient electromagnetic data: A case study from the Hawiah volcanogenic massive sulfide deposit in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jappgeo.2025.106084</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117362764</guid>
      <dc:creator>Hesham El-Kaliouby, Juntao Lu, Panagiotis Kirmizakis, Abid Khogali, Tim Eatwell, Tomos Bryan, Pantelis Soupios</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of Applied Geophysics</dc:publisher>
      <category>Induced polarization</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Sulfide</category>
      <category>Polarization (electrochemistry)</category>
      <category>Transient (computer programming)</category>
      <description>Topics: Induced polarization, Geology, Sulfide, Polarization (electrochemistry), Transient (computer programming)&#10;Venue: Journal of Applied Geophysics&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Foamed CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Dynamics during Geo-Sequestration in Deep Saline Aquifers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c04033</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117143684</guid>
      <dc:creator>Dele Nurudeen Ismaila, Afeez Gbadamosi, Jawad Al Drwish, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, Shabeeb Alajmei, Murtada Saleh Aljawad</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Energy &amp; Fuels</dc:publisher>
      <category>Aquifer</category>
      <category>Geology</category>
      <category>Environmental science</category>
      <category>Petroleum engineering</category>
      <category>Groundwater</category>
      <description>Topics: Aquifer, Geology, Environmental science, Petroleum engineering, Groundwater&#10;Venue: Energy &amp; Fuels&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gauge-Invariant Long-Wavelength TDDFT Without Empty States: From Polarizability to Kubo Conductivity Across Heterogeneous Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2512.20075</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117255705</guid>
      <dc:creator>Christian Tantardini, Quentin Pitteloud, B. Yakobson, Martin Andersson</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Dielectric</category>
      <category>Kubo formula</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Polarizability</category>
      <category>Polarization (electrochemistry)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Electromagnetic response is commonly computed in two languages: length-gauge molecular polarizabilities and velocity-gauge (Kubo) conductivities for periodic solids. We introduce a compact, gauge-invariant bridge that carries the same microscopic inputs-transition dipoles and interaction kernels-from molecules to crystals and heterogeneous media, with explicit SI prefactors and fine-structure scaling via $(α_{\rm fs})$. The long-wavelength limit is handled through a reduced dielectric matrix that retains local-field mixing, interfaces and 2D layers are treated with sheet boundary conditions (rather than naïve ultrathin films), and length-velocity equivalence is enforced in practice by including the equal-time (diamagnetic/contact) term alongside the paramagnetic current. Finite temperature is addressed on the Matsubara axis with numerically stable real-axis evaluation (complex polarization propagator), preserving unit consistency end-to-end. The framework enables predictive, unit-faithful observables from radio frequency to ultraviolet-RF/microwave heating and penetration depth, dielectric-logging contrast, interfacial optics of thin films and 2D sheets, and adsorption metrics via imaginary-axis polarizabilities. Numerical checks (gauge overlay and optical $(f)$-sum saturation) validate the implementation. Immediate priorities include compact, temperature- and salinity-aware kernels with quantified uncertainties and \emph{operando} interfacial diagnostics for integration into…&#10;Topics: Dielectric, Kubo formula, Materials science, Polarizability, Polarization (electrochemistry)&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gauge-Invariant Long-Wavelength TDDFT Without Empty States: From Polarizability to Kubo Conductivity Across Heterogeneous Materials</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W7117277276</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117277276</guid>
      <dc:creator>Christian Tantardini, Quentin Pitteloud, B. Yakobson, Martin Andersson</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Dielectric</category>
      <category>Kubo formula</category>
      <category>Materials science</category>
      <category>Polarizability</category>
      <category>Polarization (electrochemistry)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Electromagnetic response is commonly computed in two languages: length-gauge molecular polarizabilities and velocity-gauge (Kubo) conductivities for periodic solids. We introduce a compact, gauge-invariant bridge that carries the same microscopic inputs-transition dipoles and interaction kernels-from molecules to crystals and heterogeneous media, with explicit SI prefactors and fine-structure scaling via $(α_{\rm fs})$. The long-wavelength limit is handled through a reduced dielectric matrix that retains local-field mixing, interfaces and 2D layers are treated with sheet boundary conditions (rather than naïve ultrathin films), and length-velocity equivalence is enforced in practice by including the equal-time (diamagnetic/contact) term alongside the paramagnetic current. Finite temperature is addressed on the Matsubara axis with numerically stable real-axis evaluation (complex polarization propagator), preserving unit consistency end-to-end. The framework enables predictive, unit-faithful observables from radio frequency to ultraviolet-RF/microwave heating and penetration depth, dielectric-logging contrast, interfacial optics of thin films and 2D sheets, and adsorption metrics via imaginary-axis polarizabilities. Numerical checks (gauge overlay and optical $(f)$-sum saturation) validate the implementation. Immediate priorities include compact, temperature- and salinity-aware kernels with quantified uncertainties and \emph{operando} interfacial diagnostics for integration into…&#10;Topics: Dielectric, Kubo formula, Materials science, Polarizability, Polarization (electrochemistry)&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrative Dashboard (IDB)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.18027324</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117128083</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abdullah Alqubalee</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)</dc:publisher>
      <category>Dashboard</category>
      <category>Computer science</category>
      <category>World Wide Web</category>
      <category>Analytics</category>
      <category>Restructuring</category>
      <description>Abstract: An offline, data-driven research analytics app that uses locally cached OpenAlex data to keep navigation fast and accessible without relying on live API calls. It helps you explore publications and citations by topic, institution, and member over the years, inspect co-author networks and follow links to publication DOIs or URLs, and filter instantly with precomputed tables—no waiting for remote queries. The latest updates include: Enhancements to the user interface. Restructuring of files for improved organization Repairing broken links Resolving mojibake issues in CSV exports.&#10;Topics: Dashboard, Computer science, World Wide Web, Analytics, Restructuring&#10;Venue: Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaolinite Illitization Under Hydrothermal Conditions: Experimental Insight into Transformation Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min16010004</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417503339</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mashaer A. Alfaraj, Abdulwahab Muhammad Bello, Anas Muhammad Salisu, Khalid Al–Ramadan</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Minerals</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Illite plays a critical role in diagenetic processes of sedimentary rocks, influencing geochemical evolution, reservoir quality, and fluid flow pathways. This study experimentally investigated the hydrothermal transformation of kaolinite to illite using sandstones from the Upper Ordovician Quwarah Member of Qasim Formation, northwest Saudi Arabia. Experiments were performed to simulate burial diagenesis involving illitization using three fluid systems: a synthetic solution (0.2 M KCl and 0.5 M MgCl2), natural Red Sea water, and modified Red Sea water (0.2 M KCl and 0.5 M MgCl2 + Red Sea water) at different temperatures (80 °C, 150 °C, 200 °C, 250 °C). Analysis included thin-section petrography, scanning electron microscopy, and X-ray diffraction, whereas the elemental compositions of the experimental solutions were analyzed using ICP-MS and Ion Chromatography. At 80 °C and 150 °C, kaolinite underwent dissolution without significant mineralogical changes. At 200 °C, continued kaolinite disaggregation and dissolution produced smectite and mixed smectite–chlorite/illite layers, indicating early transformation pathways. At 250 °C, fluid chemistry exerted strong control on clay minerals. The synthetic solution formed smectite with minor chlorite and illite; Red Sea water favored well developed smectite; the modified Red Sea water promoted well-developed illite due to increased potassium availability. The experiments show illitization is strongly temperature dependent and primarily…&#10;Venue: Minerals&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global trends and untapped potential of critical minerals for a sustainable future in the Arabian Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exis.2025.101840</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417506769</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Zaka Emad, Arshad Raza, Mohamed Mahmoud, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, Daniyal Abbasi</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>The Extractive Industries and Society</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: The Extractive Industries and Society&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-Based Molecular Catalysts Designed for Significantly Enhanced Low-Bias Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation over BiVO &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.5c06139</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417503444</guid>
      <dc:creator>Tahir Naveed Jahangir, Muhammad Ashraf, Safwat Abdel‐Azeim, Sardaraz Khan, Nisar Ullah, Tarek A. Kandiel</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>ACS Catalysis</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: ACS Catalysis&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methylene Blue and DTAB Synergy for Wettability Modification in Saline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-025-10977-2</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417467482</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhamad Raihan Al Fikri, Shams Kalam, Mobeen Murtaza, Novia Rita, Muslim Abdurrahman, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, Arshad Raza</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Conventional and machine learning approaches with seismic inversion for optimized porosity estimation in heterogeneous siliciclastic rocks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pce.2025.104248</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417443748</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muyyassar Hussain, Urooj Shakir, Zohaib Naseer, Muhammad Raiees Amjad, Farooq Arshad, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, Ahmed E. Radwan</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Physics and Chemistry of the Earth Parts A/B/C</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Physics and Chemistry of the Earth Parts A/B/C&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-Functionalized Silica Nanomaterials for Effective CO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Foam Stabilization in Harsh Carbonate Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c04712</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417430413</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sivabalan Sakthivel</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Energy &amp; Fuels</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Energy &amp; Fuels&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A similarity model for subgrade compaction from collaborative laboratory-field tests</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trgeo.2025.101858</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417411019</guid>
      <dc:creator>Xuefei Wang, Xu Liu, Jiale Li, Jianmin Zhang, Guowei Ma</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Transportation Geotechnics</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Transportation Geotechnics&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Age Matters: A Systematic Review of Limb-Salvage Surgery Outcomes in Pediatric Versus Adult Osteosarcoma</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.99434</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417422330</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mohammed Alharbi, Raghad F Aljeaid, Fahad Althebaity, Hilal Al-Harthi, Loay Al-Ghamdi, Khalid W Idris, Alhassan Aledrissi, Omar Alharbi, Ahmed Bujbara, Raad Balobid, Dhafer Al Shehri, Abdulkreem Al-Juhani</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Cureus</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Limb-salvage surgery (LSS) is the cornerstone of modern osteosarcoma management, yet outcomes appear to differ substantially between pediatric and adult patients. Variability in tumor biology, chemotherapy tolerance, treatment intensity, and reconstructive durability may contribute to age-related disparities; however, comparative evidence has not been previously synthesized. This study aimed to systematically evaluate oncologic, functional, and prognostic differences in limb-salvage outcomes between pediatric and adult patients with osteosarcoma. A Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA)-guided systematic review was performed across major databases. Studies were eligible if they reported limb-salvage outcomes separately for pediatric and adult patients. Data extraction encompassed survival, recurrence, functional scores, chemotherapy response, and prognostic factors. Risk of bias was assessed using the Newcastle-Ottawa Scale. Seven studies met the inclusion criteria, representing over 12,000 patients from cooperative trials, national registries, and institutional cohorts. Pediatric patients consistently demonstrated superior oncologic outcomes, with higher five-year overall survival (55%-73% vs. 41%-69%) and lower distant recurrence rates compared with adults. Local recurrence remained low but was slightly more frequent in adults. Functional outcomes favored pediatric groups, who achieved higher MSTS scores and lower revision rates. Histolo…&#10;Venue: Cureus&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental study of CO2 sequestration and H2 generation potential through mineral carbonation in Saudi red mud</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-32469-x</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417497487</guid>
      <dc:creator>Khaled Al-Azani, Mohamed Gamal Rezk, Ahmed Farid Ibrahim</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Scientific Reports</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Scientific Reports&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-temperature behavior of density-functional theory for metals based on density-functional perturbation theory and Sommerfeld expansion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2512.14438</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417469600</guid>
      <dc:creator>Xavier Gonze, Christian Tantardini, Antoine Levitt</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: The temperature dependence of most solid-state properties is dominated by lattice vibrations, but metals display notable purely electronic effects at low temperature, such as the linear specific heat and the linear entropy, that were derived by Sommerfeld for the non-interacting electron gas via the low-temperature expansion of Fermi-Dirac integrals. Here we treat temperature as a perturbation within density-functional perturbation theory (DFPT). For finite temperature, we show how self-consistency screens the bare, temperature-induced density change obtained in the non-interacting picture: the inverse transpose of the electronic dielectric operator, that includes Adler-Wiser and a term related to the shift in Fermi level, links the self-consistent density response to the bare thermal density change. This approach is implemented in DFTK, and demonstrated by the computation of the second-order derivative of the free energy, and the first-order derivative of entropy for aluminum. Then, we examine the $T\!\to\!0$ limit. The finite temperature formalism contains divergences, that we cure using the Sommerfeld expansion to analyze metallic systems at 0 K. The electronic free energy is quadratic in $T$ provided the Fermi level is not at a Van Hove singularity of the density of states. If the latter happens, another temperature behavior might appear, depending on the type of Van Hove singularity, that we analyze. Our formulation applies to systems periodic in one, two, or three dimen…&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison Between the Impact of Mineralogy and Pore Geometry on Acoustic Velocity in Carbonates: Insights from Global Dataset and Rock-Physics Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/resources14120189</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417318070</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ammar El‐Husseiny</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Resources</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: The characterization of carbonate subsurface reservoirs, which host significant natural resources such as water and hydrocarbon, is crucial for earth scientists and engineers. Key characterization methods include seismic and downhole sonic techniques. This study explores the relative influence of mineralogy versus pore geometry on acoustic velocity and velocity–porosity relationships in carbonate rocks, which is important for seismic and sonic interpretation in reservoir characterization. A global dataset from ten localities encompassing different carbonate lithologies—including limestones, fabric-preserving (FP) and non-fabric-preserving (NFP) dolostones, and siliceous carbonates—was analyzed using laboratory measurements and Differential Effective Medium (DEM) modeling. Results show that the mineralogy influence decreases with porosity, so it is limited only to tight rocks where dolostones show higher velocity than limestones while siliceous carbonates show the least velocity. As porosity increases, FP dolostones retain higher velocities, whereas NFP dolostones have comparable or lower velocities than limestones, contrary to expectations from mineral elastic properties. This behavior is mainly governed by pore geometry, as supported by petrographic analysis and DEM modeling. Siliceous carbonates display notably lower velocities, which is entirely attributed to smaller pore aspect ratios (about 50% less than in limestones) rather than mineralogical effects. Overall, this stu…&#10;Venue: Resources&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MicroPhaseNO: Adapting an Earthquake-Trained Phase Neural Operator for Microseismic Phase Picking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2512.13197</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417456639</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ayrat Abdullin, Umair bin Waheed, Leo Eisner, Naveed Iqbal</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Seismic phase picking is very often used for microseismic monitoring and subsurface imaging. Traditional manual processing is not feasible for either real-time applications or large arrays. Deep learning-based pickers trained on large earthquake catalogs offer an automated alternative. However, they are typically optimized for high signal-to-noise, long-duration networks and struggle with the challenges presented by microseismic datasets, which are purpose-built for limited time without previously detected seismicity. In this study, we demonstrate how a network-wide earthquake phase picker, the Phase Neural Operator (PhaseNO), can be adapted to microseismic monitoring using transfer learning. Starting from a PhaseNO model pre-trained on more than 57,000 three-component earthquake and noise records, we fine-tune the model using only 200 labeled and noise seismograms from induced events in hydraulic-fracturing settings. The fine-tuned model thus preserves the rich spatio-temporal representation learned from abundant earthquake data, while adapting to the characteristics and labeling conventions of microseismic phases, which are often picked on peaks or troughs rather than onsets. We evaluate performance on three distinct real-world microseismic datasets with different network geometries and acquisition parameters. Compared to the original PhaseNO and a conventional workflow, the adapted model increases F1 score and accuracy by up to 30%, and strongly reduces systematic timing b…&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pix2Geomodel: A next-generation reservoir geomodeling with property-to-property translation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoen.2025.214342</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417279471</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abdulrahman Al‐Fakih, Ardiansyah Koeshidayatullah, Nabil A. Saraih, Tapan Mukerji, Rayan Kanfar, Abdulmohsen Alali, SanLinn I. Kaka</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Geoenergy Science and Engineering</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Geoenergy Science and Engineering&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative use of chitosan salt for enhanced CO2 capture and wellbore injectivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoen.2025.214335</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417166612</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed K. Al-Yasiri, Usama Alameedy, Hani Al Mukainah, Mahmoud A. Abdulhamid, Ahmed Al‐Yaseri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Geoenergy Science and Engineering</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Geoenergy Science and Engineering&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process optimization and reaction kinetics of heterogeneous nitration of naphthalene in microreactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.171616</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417123806</guid>
      <dc:creator>Chengxiang He, Congying Zhang, Syed Muhammad Shakil Hussain, Kenechukwu George UGWU, Chunying Zhu, Youguang Ma, Taotao Fu</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Chemical Engineering Journal</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Chemical Engineering Journal&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prospective routes for the synthesis of graphene-based hydrogels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-31448-3.00002-1</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417062703</guid>
      <dc:creator>Aqeel Ahmad, Masooma Nazar, A. Vijaya Bhaskar Reddy, Othman Charles S. Al Hamouz, Syed Muhammad Shakil Hussain, Muhammad Moniruzzaman</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Elsevier eBooks</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Elsevier eBooks&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of contributors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-31448-3.00031-8</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417063028</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abdelali Aboussabek, Hussaini Adam, Muhammad Afzal, Syed Riyaz Ahammed, Aqeel Ahmad, Adenike A. Akinsemolu, Othman Charles S. Al Hamouz, Fariha Aman, Dedy Anwar, Asma Ashraf, Farrukh Azeem, Rachid Aziam, Shahid Bashir, Fakhra Batool, Alakesh Bharali, Nikhil Biswas, C. Pavani, Hleko Chauke, Mohamed Chiban, D. Venkatesh, Nirmala Devi, Rituraj Dubey, Farid Fadhillah, N.K. Farhana, G Divya Jyothi, Sharanabasava V. Ganachari, Gangaraju Gedda, Subash C.B. Gopinath, Sumreen Hayat, Leena V. Hublikar, Muhammad Ijaz, Abongile Jijana, Fathiah Kamarulazam, H.R. Khan, Huma Warsi Khan, Susankar Kushari, Damiki Laloo, Kah Hoe Loh, Lerato Machogo-Phao, V. Madhavi, Narender Malothu, Melaku Dereje Mamo, L. Mampane, Nonkululeko Miya, Nosipho Moloto, William Moloto, Muhammad Moniruzzaman, Mahesh P. More, Mathato P. Motaung, Nawshad Muhammad, Saima Muzammil, Arunadevi Natarajan, Masooma Nazar, Sadhana Noothi, Safa Nouaa, Bulelwa Ntsendwana, Balaji Padya, Shyam S. Pandey, Myung‐Geol Pang, Kalpesh Ramlal Patil, Narendra B. Patil, Amol R. Pawar, Thibeorchews Prasankumar, Vishnu Pulavarthy, MI Qureshi, Harshita Rai, K. Ramesh, S. Ramesh, Ijaz Rasul, Nowduru Ravikiran, A. Vijaya Bhaskar Reddy, Aneela Regala, Hana Safitri, Bhanu P. Sahu, Muhammad Saqalein, Muhammad Saria, Adi Setiawan, Manoj Kumar Shah, Syed Muhammad Shakil Hussain, Muhammad Hussnain Siddique, Lucky Sikhwivhilu, Kshitij RB Singh, N. Sivakumar, Daniela Simina Ștefan, Hari Chandana T., Ramesh Thotakura, V.L.N. Balaji Gupta Tiruveedhi, Asad Ullah, Venkatramana Losetty, Yudha Gusti Wibowo, Y. B. R. D. Rajesh, Tehreem Zahra, Mohamed Zerbet, Yaschlewal Zigyalew, Muhammad Zubair, Muhammad Zulfajri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Elsevier eBooks</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Elsevier eBooks&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights Into Barite Particle Size and Perlite Integration to Advanced Drilling Fluids Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1115/1.4070562</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416993484</guid>
      <dc:creator>Jaber Al Jaberi, Badr Bageri, Anas Alsaleem, Yazeed Alshehri, Shirish Patil</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of energy resources technology.</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract Barite is a widely used weighting material in water-based drilling muds (WBMs) due to its high specific gravity and cost-effectiveness. However, variations in barite particle size distribution (PSD) can significantly impact drilling fluid performance, influencing properties such as filtration, rheology, and formation damage. This study examines the influence of barite PSD on these key properties and explores the potential of perlite as an additive to enhance drilling fluid performance. To achieve this, three barite grades with distinct PSDs were prepared using sieving and ball milling. These were used to formulate three distinct drilling muds, which were then characterized and tested through laboratory analyses, including particle size analysis, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), x-ray diffraction (XRD), and high-pressure high-temperature (HPHT) filtration tests. The methodology aimed to evaluate the effects of PSD variations and perlite addition on filtration behavior, filter cake characteristics, and rheological properties. The results demonstrated that barite PSD significantly affects drilling fluid properties. Smaller barite particles enhanced mud stability and minimized filtration issues, whereas larger particles increased filter cake thickness and permeability, potentially leading to greater formation damage. Notably, the addition of perlite improved rheological stability, reduced filter cake thickness, and optimized overall fluid performance, with the most si…&#10;Venue: Journal of energy resources technology.&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on Applications of Chelating Agents in Enhanced Oil Recovery: Advances and Outlook</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c04766</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416952831</guid>
      <dc:creator>Abdul Ahad Manzoor, Xiao Deng, Mohammed Alotaibi, Mohanad Fahmi, Syed Muhammad Shakil Hussain, Mohamed Mahmoud, Muhammad Shahzad Kamal, Shirish Patil</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Energy &amp; Fuels</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Energy &amp; Fuels&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-driven acoustic impedance inversion with globally optimized reservoir characterization for reserve estimation in carbonate reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.108571</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416956848</guid>
      <dc:creator>Lutfi Mulyadi Surachman, Abdulazeez Abdulraheem, SanLinn I. Kaka, Abdullatif Al‐Shuhail</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Results in Engineering</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Results in Engineering&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation damage assessment in carbonate reservoirs after removing hematite-water-based filter cake using HCl</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-29161-5</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416930832</guid>
      <dc:creator>Amir Shokry, Salaheldin Elkatatny, Badr Bageri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Scientific Reports</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Scientific Reports&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sedimentological and diagenetic controls on burrow fillings in the upper Jurassic Hanifa formation, central Saudi Arabia: Implications for porosity and pore system variations in bioturbated reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsrc.2025.11.007</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416957423</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Refaat, Hassan A. Eltom, Ammar El‐Husseiny, John Humphrey, Moaz Salih</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>International Journal of Sediment Research</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: International Journal of Sediment Research&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groundwater science in the age of AI: emerging paradigms and challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asr.2025.11.099</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416868394</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mahfuzur Rahman, Asif Raihan, Syed Masiur Rahman, Md Anuwer Hossain, Mohammed Benaafi, Isam H. Aljundi</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Advances in Space Research</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Advances in Space Research&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of salinity on gas-water capillary pressure behavior in carbonate reservoirs: Implications of underground gas storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ees.2025.11.005</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4417193707</guid>
      <dc:creator>R. B. Fahim, Shabeeb Alajmei, Ahmed Al‐Yaseri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Earth energy science.</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Earth energy science.&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Kinetic Insights into Biomass and Biosurfactant Production for Enhanced Oil Recovery Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/231828-pa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W7117545063</guid>
      <dc:creator>Maysoon Awadh, S. M. Zakir Hossain, Shaker Haji, Israa Mohammed AlHammar, Elias Ahmed Alsaei, Hussain A. Safar, Nahid Sultana, Nasiru Salahu Muhammed, Bashirul Haq</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SPE Journal</dc:publisher>
      <category>Enhanced oil recovery</category>
      <category>Support vector machine</category>
      <category>Coefficient of determination</category>
      <category>Biomass (ecology)</category>
      <category>Benchmark (surveying)</category>
      <description>Abstract: Summary Enhanced oil recovery (EOR) using biosurfactants has gained significant attention due to its cost-effectiveness and environmental compatibility. In this study, we introduce a hybrid modeling approach that combines the Bayesian optimization algorithm (BOA) with support vector regression (SVR) to predict rhamnolipid production by Pseudomonas aeruginosa MYSAG. In addition, we assess the produced biosurfactant for its potential application in microbial EOR (MEOR) using experimental data for model development, and benchmark the predictive performance of the hybrid BOA-SVR model against the conventional response surface methodology (RSM) using multiple statistical indicators. Compared with the RSM model, the proposed hybrid model exhibits superior predictive accuracy, achieving more than a 95% improvement in mean absolute percentage error (MAPE), along with lower mean absolute error (MAE), relative error (RE), and root mean square error (RMSE), as well as a higher coefficient of determination (R2 = 0.9833). We use additional simulated data to validate the hybrid BOA-SVR model’s generalization ability, and analyze the kinetics of bacterial growth and biosurfactant production using the logistic and Luedeking-Piret (LP) models, revealing a growth-associated production pattern. We further evaluate the efficacy of the produced biosurfactants in MEOR through interfacial tension (IFT) and zeta potential measurements. At a concentration of 0.27 wt%, the IFT decreases significantly …&#10;Topics: Enhanced oil recovery, Support vector machine, Coefficient of determination, Biomass (ecology), Benchmark (surveying)&#10;Venue: SPE Journal&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gradual deletion of diacritics from reading text for learners of Arabic for non-native speakers at the advanced level: &quot; experimental study &quot;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.65073/1658-9343.1084</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416939443</guid>
      <dc:creator>Dhafer Al Shehri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>UB Journal for Humanities</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: UB Journal for Humanities&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Limb Salvage Using a Distally Based Peroneus Brevis Flap for Distal Tibial Osteomyelitis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.98065</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416814672</guid>
      <dc:creator>Awatif Al-Mubarak, Jenna A Almannaei, Qasim Alnahawi, Mohamed Mahmoud</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Cureus</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Cureus&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of temperature on CO2 corrosion inhibition by black tea extract: A combined experimental and molecular modelling study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101271</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416818579</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ghada Shaban, Emad Hasan Bartawi, Martin Andersson, Rajan Ambat</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Materials Today Sustainability</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Materials Today Sustainability&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial neural network (ANN) based prediction of proppant settling in horizontal wellbores during hydraulic fracturing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-26458-3</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416764361</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mahmoud Jumaa, Shabeeb Alajmei, Amjed Hassan, Ashtiwi Bahri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Scientific Reports</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract Proppant transport and settling in horizontal wellbores is a major challenge in hydraulic fracturing, leading to problems such as sand production, equipment wear, wellbore blockages, and reduced production rates. Traditional empirical models are often limited in accuracy because the physical relationships involved are highly nonlinear and complex. In this study, Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) were used to develop predictive models for sand settling in horizontal wellbores during hydraulic fracturing. In this work, the data were obtained from controlled laboratory experiments that simulated horizontal wellbore sections with different perforation clusters. Key parameters such as proppant diameter, injection rate, perforation orientation, and number of perforations were analyzed. Two ANN models were developed: Model A used all nine measured parameters, while Model B used five selected parameters identified through correlation analysis. Model performance was evaluated using statistical metrics including the coefficient of determination (R²), Average Absolute Difference (AAD), Root Mean Squared Error (RMSE), and Mean Absolute Percentage Error (MAPE). Additionally, comparative analyses with Random Forest and Gradient Boosting algorithms confirmed the superior performance of the ANN models, and an explicit neural-network-based correlation was formulated for direct engineering use. Results show that Model A achieved an R² of 0.96 and Model B achieved 0.89, demonstrating t…&#10;Venue: Scientific Reports&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seismic characterization of inland and coastal sabkhas using VP, VS, seismic anisotropy, and attenuation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-29863-w</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416764301</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Eleslambouly, Mohammed Y. Ali, Fateh Bouchaala, Ammar El‐Husseiny, Abdullatif Al‐Shuhail, Sherif M. Hanafy, Jun Matsushima</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Scientific Reports</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Scientific Reports&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced soil carbonation strategies: insights into quantification, performance, and scalable carbon capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100551</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416713239</guid>
      <dc:creator>Aaqib Ali, Arshad Raza, Mubashir Aziz, Mohamed E. Mahmoud, Umair Ali, Ammar Mohammed Alshammari</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Accelerated soil carbonation (ASC) is a rapidly advancing carbon capture and storage technique which provides a dual benefit of permanent CO2 sequestration and geotechnical soil stabilization. This paper presents a comprehensive review of soil carbonation processes, emphasizing the mechanisms, quantification methods, and engineering performance improvements achieved through MgO and CaO-based binders and industrial by-products. The carbonation process transforms reactive oxides into stable carbonate minerals, enhancing soil strength, stiffness, and durability while reducing moisture content and porosity. A systematic analysis of the impact of carbonation on physical, chemical, mechanical, and microstructural behavior is presented, together with quantification approaches such as thermogravimetric analysis, calcimetry, and gas-balance techniques. The techno-economic evaluation highlights that optimized magnesia-lime-slag systems can offset up to 70 % of embodied emissions, offering a cost-effective and scalable pathway for carbon-negative ground improvement. Despite these advances, the field faces challenges related to reaction uniformity, long-term durability, and standardization of quantification and field protocols. The study identifies key research directions to establish ASC as a reliable, sustainable, and verifiable carbon sequestration strategy in geotechnical engineering.&#10;Venue: Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformer-Based Generative Model for Automated Field Development Planning and Optimization in Hydrocarbon Reservoirs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/231418-pa</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416703739</guid>
      <dc:creator>Menhal A. Al-Ismael, Abeeb A. Awotunde</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SPE Journal</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Summary As global demand for energy is increasing, exploration and new discoveries of oil and gas reservoirs continue, with optimal field development becoming more critical. Field development planning requires a comprehensive understanding of the reservoir, which usually involves developing computer-based simulation models and using time-intensive optimization techniques. Recent progress in generative artificial intelligence (AI) indicates potential to support field development optimization (FDO). With this research, we investigate the application of generative AI in FDO by developing a transformer-based generative model for generating optimal future wells that maximize the net present value (NPV). A new transformer architecture is developed, and the corresponding model is trained and applied to generate two outputs: (i) a probability map, providing spatial scores that guide the optimization of well types and locations, and (ii) a well control map that specifies the optimal operating settings at each location. The architecture includes an encoder module, which captures complex patterns and dependencies within the numerical simulation data to support well placement decisions. It also includes an embedding layer that converts raw data into dense vectors and encoding layers that add spatial and temporal context to improve model understanding of reservoir dynamics. The proposed approach was evaluated using the PUNQ-S3 benchmark reservoir simulation model using various input scena…&#10;Venue: SPE Journal&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Photoelectric Logs in Challenging Conditions Using Machine Learning and Statistical Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/230435-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416589455</guid>
      <dc:creator>Eassa Abdullah, Reem AlYami, Subhan Aliyev, Salaheldin Elkatatny</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference and Exhibition</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract The photoelectric (PEF) log measures the photoelectric absorption factor, pivotal for determining rock matrix properties. High absorption factor values are typical in limestones, dolomites, clay, iron-bearing minerals, and heavy minerals, whereas sandstones exhibit lower values. In this study, actual photoelectric logs were gathered from the field alongside various other logs such as gallons per minute (GPM), standpipe pressure (SPP), rate of penetration (ROP), and bulk density (RHOB). Utilizing a suite of machine learning regression techniques—ridge regression, linear regression, support vector machines (SVM), polynomial regression, random forest, and decision tree—this research aimed to predict the photoelectric logs using porosity and other log data as inputs. The effectiveness of these models was confirmed through their strong predictive accuracy relative to actual log values. The ensemble of regression models demonstrated significant correlation coefficients and low root mean square errors, illustrating their robust capability to predict photoelectric data at various depths based on available drilling data.&#10;Venue: SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference and Exhibition&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper spray analysis of crude oil samples: comparing traditional characterization schemes with mass spectrometric outcomes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijms.2025.117554</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416640793</guid>
      <dc:creator>Theis I. Sølling, Nathan F. Dalleska, Syed Sajjad Hussain, J. L. Beauchamp</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>International Journal of Mass Spectrometry</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: International Journal of Mass Spectrometry&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Stability and Rheology of Oil-Based Drilling Fluids with a Novel Organoclay Additive for HPHT Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/230351-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416591109</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Abdulhamid Mahmoud, Rahul Gajbhiye, Salaheldin Elkatatny</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference and Exhibition</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract The performance of oil-based drilling fluids (OBDFs) is often compromised under high-pressure and high-temperature (HPHT) conditions, where emulsion instability, barite sag, and rheological breakdown become critical concerns. This study investigates the use of Claytone-EM, a commercial organoclay (OC), as a rheological and stabilization additive to improve OBDF behavior in such challenging environments. Claytone-EM was characterized using X-ray diffraction (XRD), X-ray fluorescence (XRF), particle size distribution (PSD), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) to determine its mineralogical and morphological attributes. The additive was incorporated into an HPHT-grade OBDF and compared to a conventional OC (MC-TONE) across multiple performance metrics, including electrical stability, sag resistance (both static and dynamic), rheology, and filtration behavior. Tests were conducted at 275°F and 500 psi to simulate downhole conditions. The Claytone-EM formulation exhibited enhanced electrical stability, reduced sag tendency under static and circulating conditions, and improved gel strength. Rheological measurements showed increased yield point and better flow behavior at low shear rates, supporting improved cuttings transport. In HPHT filtration tests, Claytone-EM contributed to lower fluid loss and thinner, more compact filter cakes. These results demonstrate that Claytone-EM can strengthen OBDF performance in HPHT wells by enhancing fluid structure, suspension stabili…&#10;Venue: SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference and Exhibition&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Blending in Australian Gas Network: A Simulation Study of Riverland Pipeline System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/230438-ms</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416589389</guid>
      <dc:creator>Hiral Jain, Mohammed Hasnain Saiyed, Arshad Khan, Bashirul Haq, Mohamed Mahmoud</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference and Exhibition</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract Hydrogen blending with natural gas (H2-NG blending) is a practical way to reduce and address the carbon impact of using natural gas while offering a cost-effective way to transport huge amounts of H2. This study aims to evaluate the Riverland pipeline system located in Australia. The study provides information on how different H2 concentrations in the gas mixture affect the pipeline&apos;s erosional velocity ratio (EVR), corrosion rates, and pressure performance. The Riverland Transmission Pipeline was built to convey the gas travel though Angaston gate and compressor station to Berri gate station and later distribute the gas in Berri region. The Riverland Pipeline has a number of farm taps and the lateral pipeline joining the Riverland Pipeline at Sedan and the township of Murray Bridge. The pipeline is 314km long and have diameter of 114mm with an MAOP of 10,000kPa and capacity of 5.6 TJ/day. We took a novel technique and created a simulation model in PIPESIM-Net software that incorporates a GIS map to compute pressure drops, precisely record topographical profiles, and accurately imitate steady state gaseous flow. In addition to specifying nodes (sink/source) with suitable boundary conditions, it also considers aspects like pipeline specifications, elevation, and the gas composition. The results indicate that the corrosion rate increases slightly with increasing H2 concentration, reaching its highest at 80% H2 followed by decrease in corrosion rate at every 10% decreas…&#10;Venue: SPE Annual Caspian Technical Conference and Exhibition&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Bioturbation on Sandstone Brittleness: Insights from the Qassim Formation, Northwestern Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-025-10871-x</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416608146</guid>
      <dc:creator>Moaz Salih, Hassan A. Eltom, Ammar El‐Husseiny, Korhan Ayrancı</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urban expansion and warming jointly amplify drought and surface heat island effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2025.2586775</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416556497</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mahfuzur Rahman, Zulfiqar Hammad, Hyeong-Joo Kim, Seonju Lee, Tae-Woong Park, Hyeong-Soo Kim, Md Masudur Rahman, Md Anuwer Hossain, Mohammed Benaafi, Isam H. Aljundi, Mohammed Benaafi, Isam H. Aljundi</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Geocarto International</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Urbanization and climate change are intensifying the co-occurrence of drought and surface urban heat island (SUHI) effects, yet their combined dynamics remain poorly understood at high spatial resolution. This study evaluates the compound risk of drought and UHI in South Korea&apos;s Saemangeum region using a hybrid KNN–LSTM model, alongside three comparative approaches (KNN, CNN, CNN–LSTM), incorporating CMIP6 climate projections and satellite-derived land metrics. The KNN–LSTM model demonstrated superior performance (R² = 0.94; MSE = 0.0053), accurately capturing an increasing drought–SUHI association, which rose from 0.84 (1991–2020) to 1.00 by 2100 under the SSP585 scenario. High-risk zones predominantly overlap with built-up and cropland areas, where UHI indices exceed 4.0 and drought probabilities surpass 0.9. Although land use explains over 80% of drought variability under baseline conditions, its predictive power diminishes under future warming, highlighting the growing role of climate feedbacks. These findings emphasize the emergence of synchronized thermal and hydrological stressors in urbanizing coastal regions and underscore the need for integrated land-climate adaptation strategies supported by machine learning-based early warning systems.&#10;Venue: Geocarto International&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Charge Dynamics in Carbon Nanodot-Methyl Viologen Systems: Ultrafast Electron Transfer and Suppressed Recombination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.5c04871</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416506251</guid>
      <dc:creator>Manas R. Parida, Sivabalan Sakthivel, Amal Hassan Tolba, Theis I. Sølling, Ahmed M. El‐Zohry</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>The Journal of Physical Chemistry C</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: The Journal of Physical Chemistry C&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A combined experimental and first-principles study of tungsten ditelluride (WTe2) Weyl semimetal structure and optical characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1140/epjp/s13360-025-07071-9</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416528720</guid>
      <dc:creator>Sheena Shah, Kh. A. Ziq, Ahmed M. El‐Zohry, Said M. Al Azar, Anas Y. Al‐Reyahi, Watheq Al‐Basheer</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>The European Physical Journal Plus</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: The European Physical Journal Plus&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Advances and challenges in geological CO2 sequestration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2025.1744673</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416453425</guid>
      <dc:creator>Muhammad Hammad Rasool, Arshad Raza, Maqsood Ahmad</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Frontiers in Earth Science</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Frontiers in Earth Science&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ursolic acid enhances social behavior and modulates Th1, Th17, and T regulatory cell-related transcription factor signaling in the BTBR T+ Itpr3tf/J mouse model of autism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2025.578810</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416423729</guid>
      <dc:creator>Thamer H. Albekairi, Albandary AlBakheet, Talal H Alosaimi, Saleh A. Bakheet, Ahmed Nadeem, Sabry M. Attia, Mushtaq Ahmad Ansari, Marwa H. Hussein, Mohamed Mahmoud, Sheikh F. Ahmad</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of Neuroimmunology</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Journal of Neuroimmunology&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not much to show for it: Late Pleistocene dynamics of migrating megadunes in the Rub’ al-Khali, Saudi Arabia, indicate minimal preservation of their deposits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/g53651.1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416432155</guid>
      <dc:creator>Charlie S. Bristow, Nicholas Lancaster, Khalid Al–Ramadan, Christina M. Neudorf, Amanda Keen‐Zebert</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Geology</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Abstract Luminescence dating of interdune sabkha sediments and cross strata deposited on the lee face of a 160-m-high mega-crescentic dune in the eastern Rub’ al-Khali sand sea provides information on dune dynamics and preservation potential. Optically stimulated luminescence ages show that the rates of dune accumulation varied during the latest Pleistocene and Holocene. Sedimentary structures indicate that megadune migration was the result of strong northwesterly “Shamal” winds. During the same interval of the late Pleistocene and early Holocene, linear dunes in the northeastern United Arab Emirates were also accumulating rapidly, indicating that the period 16–9 ka was characterized by regionally widespread dune formation and/or reworking. The dune has subsequently migrated to the SSE almost 900 m since the early Holocene, at an average rate of 77 m/k.y., indicating persistence of the Shamal wind system for at least 20 k.y. Rates of megadune migration and wet sabkha accumulation reveal that, despite their very large size, less than 1% of the megadune would be preserved in a sedimentary record.&#10;Venue: Geology&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Assisted Decision-Making Models for Disaster Forecasting, Risk Mitigation, and Emergency Response Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.71443/9789349552081-10</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416459051</guid>
      <dc:creator>Shirish Patil, Gajendra Singh, Sridharan Rajalakshmi</dc:creator>
      <description>Abstract: The accelerating frequency and complexity of natural and anthropogenic disasters have necessitated the emergence of intelligent frameworks capable of transforming disaster management from reactive response to proactive governance. Artificial Intelligence (AI)-assisted decision-making models have become integral to forecasting hazards, assessing risks, and coordinating emergency responses with precision and efficiency. This chapter presents a comprehensive examination of the conceptual, theoretical, and computational underpinnings of AI-driven decision-making in disaster forecasting, risk mitigation, and emergency response coordination. The discussion highlights the integration of machine learning, deep learning, and probabilistic models for multi-hazard prediction, spatial-temporal analysis, and real-time decision support. It explores the role of reinforcement learning in adaptive risk management, the use of simulation-based systems for preventive strategies, and the development of hybrid AI architectures that enhance policy responsiveness. By synthesizing global case studies, empirical findings, and computational frameworks, the chapter provides insights into the transformation of disaster governance through intelligent automation and predictive analytics. The research also identifies existing gaps and technological limitations, emphasizing the need for explainable, interoperable, and ethically aligned AI systems. The integration of AI within policy and institutional structu…&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of an ANN-Driven Empirical Equation for Real-Time Prediction of Natural Gas Flow through Surface Well Chokes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15377/2409-787x.2025.12.5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416308751</guid>
      <dc:creator>Ashraf Ahmed, Ahmed A. Mahmoud, Murtada A. Elhaj, Salaheldin Elkatatny</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>International Journal of Petroleum Technology</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: To maximize production efficiency, natural gas flow via surface well chokes must be optimized. The nonlinear character of this flow frequently causes problems for conventional empirical correlations and mechanistic models. To accurately forecast gas flow rates using field data, this study develops an Artificial Neural Network (ANN) model that considers temperature, gas gravity, choke size, and pressures. The main innovation is that the optimized network is used to derive an exact, closed-form empirical equation, going beyond the typical &quot;black-box&quot; use of ANN. This equation enables the estimation of flow rate in real-time without requiring the execution of the ANN model, providing engineers with a valuable tool at present. The 5-neuron optimized ANN demonstrated remarkable accuracy, with training and testing average absolute percentage errors (AAPE) below 2% and a correlation coefficient (R) over 0.99. When tested on unknown data, the resultant equation performed well (R=0.999, AAPE=2.78%), outperforming conventional techniques in terms of generalization and predictive power. By connecting data-driven analytics with field operational realities for well management, this research represents a significant leap forward.&#10;Venue: International Journal of Petroleum Technology&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethomeen C/15 surfactant enhances CO2 mineralization in oilfield produced water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.128944</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416470830</guid>
      <dc:creator>Mohamed Abdelnaby Oraby, Israa S. Abu‐Mahfouz, Ahmed Al‐Yaseri</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of Molecular Liquids</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Journal of Molecular Liquids&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Émergence de Pseudomonas aeruginosa multirésistant dans les infections cutanées d’origine communautaire</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fander.2025.09.340</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416160737</guid>
      <dc:creator>L. Ben Afia, N. Ben Salah, Mohamed Mahmoud, Maha Bhouri, M. Youssef, H. Belhadjali, Maha Mastouri, J. Zili</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Annales de Dermatologie et de Vénéréologie - FMC</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Annales de Dermatologie et de Vénéréologie - FMC&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cenozoic Subduction Polarity Reversal Within the Celebes Sea Inferred from Teleseismic Tomography</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/essoar.176296592.24127327/v1</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416147219</guid>
      <dc:creator>Yingbo Li, Nicholas Rawlinson, Simone Pilia, Lintang Kesumastuti, ChuanChuan Lü, Sri Widiyantoro, Tianyao Hao</dc:creator>
      <description>Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a Teaching Programme Help Reduce Radiation Exposure During Extra-Capsular Proximal Femur Fracture Fixation?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.96585</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416112719</guid>
      <dc:creator>Oliver Mitchell, João Xavier, Qamar Mustafa, Mohamed Mahmoud, Rebecca Mills</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Cureus</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: Background Proximal femur fractures (PFFs) represent a major healthcare burden in the United Kingdom, with approximately 76,000 cases annually. Extra-capsular fractures are commonly treated with Dynamic Hip Screws (DHS), short or long intramedullary nails (IMNs), all of which require intraoperative fluoroscopy. Consequently, orthopaedic surgeons and patients are exposed to ionising radiation and the associated stochastic and deterministic risks. Despite regulations under the Ionising Radiation (Medical Exposure) Regulations 2017 (IR(ME)R), a wide variation in radiation safety knowledge persists, and there are no established benchmarks for acceptable exposure. This audit aims to assess whether a departmental teaching programme could reduce radiation exposure during extra-capsular PFF fixation and to explore differences between consultant and trainee-led cases. Methodology This audit was conducted at Dorset County Hospital, United Kingdom, audit number 6323. Patients with closed extra-capsular PFFs managed using DHS, short or long IMN fixations were included. Radiation exposure, expressed as dose-area product (DAP), was recorded from the Picture Archiving and Communication System (PACS) across two audit cycles: before and after delivery of an educational programme, emphasising radiological stewardship and safety. Statistical analysis was performed using independent t-tests, with significance set at &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt; &lt; 0.05 and effect sizes reported using Cohen&apos;s &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;. Results A tota…&#10;Venue: Cureus&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foraminiferal Paleoecology and Sequence Stratigraphy of the upper Dhruma Formation, Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1127/nos/2025/0877</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416072661</guid>
      <dc:creator>Chernoh Mohamed Jalloh, Adam Fheed, Frans van Buchem, Michael A. Kaminski</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Newsletters on Stratigraphy</dc:publisher>
      <description>Venue: Newsletters on Stratigraphy&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Buckley--Leverett for Multicomponent Flow in Fractured Media: Isothermal Equation-of-State Coupling and Dynamic Capillarity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2511.06233</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416157214</guid>
      <dc:creator>Christian Tantardini, Fernando Alonso-Marroquín</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>arXiv (Cornell University)</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: We present an isothermal Global Buckley--Leverett framework for multicomponent, multiphase flow in porous and fractured media that retains the interpretability of classical Buckley--Leverett while incorporating essential physics: equation of state-based phase behavior, multicomponent Maxwell--Stefan diffusion, dynamic capillarity, stress-sensitive permeability, and non-Darcy fracture flow. The formulation yields a single global-pressure equation driving the total Darcy flux and an exact fractional-flow decomposition of phase velocities with buoyancy and capillary drifts; inertial effects enter as per-phase damping that renormalizes mobilities. Crucially, the combination of Maxwell--Stefan diffusion and dynamic capillarity renders transport pseudo-parabolic, resolving the loss of strict hyperbolicity that plagues three-phase Buckley--Leverett and ensuring a well-posed initial-value problem. In practice, each time step solves the scalar global-pressure equation, reconstructs phase fluxes via the split, and advances strictly conservative component balances; axisymmetric (cylindrical) forms for radial injection with vertical buoyancy are provided. The model reduces exactly to classical Buckley--Leverett when added physics are disabled, making it a practical backbone for carbon storage and contaminant transport in fractured, compositionally complex reservoirs.&#10;Venue: arXiv (Cornell University)&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Active Sites for Catalytic Steam Reforming of Methane from Oscillations in the Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5c11696</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4416004029</guid>
      <dc:creator>Yu Zhang, Qian Wang, Peter Glarborg, Martin Andersson, Jakob Birkedal Wagner, Keld Johansen, Thomas Klint Torp, J.‐C. Grivel, Anker Degn Jensen, Chaofeng Hou, Wei Ge, Jakob Munkholt Christensen</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Journal of the American Chemical Society</dc:publisher>
      <description>Abstract: A new oscillating catalytic reaction is discovered: steam reforming of CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; in the presence of SO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; over Rh nanoparticles. The reducing products from the reforming reaction convert SO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to adsorbed sulfur, which causes deactivation. When activity, and thus the reducing environment, is lost, the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O oxidizes adsorbed S back into gaseous SO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, and activity re-emerges via a transient, S-free, but less active metastable state. Electron microscopy, spectroscopy, and theoretical calculations show that adsorption of S drives a reconstruction of the particle edges, which is reversed when H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O oxidizes away the sulfur. The reconstructions during S-adsorption alter the particle edges decorated by (211) steps into edges decorated with a (110) step. Our theoretical calculations reveal that the (211) configuration is an order of magnitude more active for reforming and identifies the reconstructed edges as the metastable state. The cycling between the presence and absence of the active (211) step sites thus leads to the discontinuity in activity that results in sustained oscillations. The correlation between activity and the presence of (211) step sites identifies these as the primary active sites for the industrially important catalytic reforming of methane. These results illustrate how heterogeneous catalysts can be extremely sensitive to the detailed configuration of the active site, such as steps with a certain structure. As …&#10;Venue: Journal of the American Chemical Society&#10;Year: 2025&#10;Citations: 0</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>